Steven Heidel | Résumé

 \mathbf{z} +1 (650) 944 9541 • \mathbf{z} steven@heidel.ca • \mathbf{z} stevenheidel

Summary

Software engineer with 4 years experience building scalable applications. Functional programming advocate. Engineering team lead. Former startup founder. Fluent in Java 8, Scala, and Ruby. Familiar with Javascript, Python, and Kotlin. Experienced in Play, Rails, Elasticsearch, Kafka, Samza, and Spark. Proud Canadian.

Experience

LinkedIn San Francisco, CA

Staff Software Engineer

December 2016-Present

- Lead engineer on the Enterprise Platform (EP) team. EP provides common functionality such as license management, external integrations, and access control to all enterprise applications at LinkedIn.
- Rebuilt enterprise search platform from the ground up to use Elasticsearch. This increased maintainability and led to a 10x decrease in cost as well as significant performance improvements. Used Spark to build offline indexes.
- Led team to migrate Sales Navigator from a legacy system to EP which was needed to close a big customer
- Gave company-wide engineering presentation on functional programming and composition in Java 8

LinkedIn Sunnyvale, CA

Senior Software Engineer

September 2015–December 2016

- O Worked on LinkedIn Lookup: the fastest way to find, learn about, and contact anyone at your company
- o Architected the API server using Scala and Play to communicate with the web and mobile apps
- Worked with growth and messaging teams to optimize member communications from actions generated by the app using Kafka and Samza for the data pipeline
- Maintainer of open source Scala library called Clump which automatically optimizes microservice calls, providing a powerful and composable interface for aggregating resources. Ported to Java as well.

LinkedIn Mountain View, CA

Software Engineer

August 2014-September 2015

- Worked on Campaign Manager, a product which advertisers use to manage \$400M+ worth of campaigns per year
- Added key features such as targeting selection and segment reports
- o Refactored inefficient parts of the application to create a faster and better user experience

Encore Toronto, ON

Co-Founder and CTO

March 2013-August 2014

- \circ Encore was a four-person startup created through The Next 36 program
- Developed prototype in Ruby on Rails, then rewrote it to be entirely non-blocking using Scala and Play
- Used REST APIs to collect photos and videos from across the web and match them up with local events

University of Saskatchewan

Saskatoon, SK

Research Assistant

July 2014-August 2014

- Assisted Dr. Artur Sowa, a professor in the Mathematics Department, on numerical simulations relating to Adiabatic Quantum Computing
- Optimized MATLAB algorithms to increase speed of the calculation by 100x

Education

University of Saskatchewan

Saskatoon, SK

B.Sc. (High Honours) in Computer Science, Minor in Mathematics September 2009–April 2014
Selected as Computer Science Valedictorian for academic achievement and involvement